<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing Journal on Dr. Juan Carlos Galán Hernández</title>
    <link>http://juancgalan.com/categories/writing-journal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing Journal on Dr. Juan Carlos Galán Hernández</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 19:50:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://juancgalan.com/categories/writing-journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast-Writes (WJ #8)</title>
      <link>http://juancgalan.com/post/writers-journal-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 19:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://juancgalan.com/post/writers-journal-8/</guid>
      <description>How does your outward appearance (i.e. cloting, makeup, hairstyle, accessories, etc.) reflect your cultural identity? My cultural identity is expressed by my choice of comfort cloths and practical hair style. My day usually revolves around academia, fitness and creativity. It can be seen as a lazy style. However, my choice of not having a car, training every day and be as active as I can as a teacher makes some type of clothes uncomfortable and impractical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating Ideas (WJ #7)</title>
      <link>http://juancgalan.com/post/writers-journal-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 19:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://juancgalan.com/post/writers-journal-7/</guid>
      <description>Some people feel generating ideas as an elusive task. Something that only great minds can do. However, most of the time we can generate ideas.
Generating ideas is a skill, and as such, it must be practiced. The first main problem is that western cultures lately are focused on the outside. How we look, how we sound, etc. This makes us worry not to said or do anything that may seem silly to others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on Collaboration (WJ #4)</title>
      <link>http://juancgalan.com/post/writers-journal-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 18:17:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://juancgalan.com/post/writers-journal-4/</guid>
      <description>Collaborative working is present in all aspects of our life. From school work to our jobs to our home. Learning to work with others is a fundamental skill in our society. Collaborate with others on a project may allow to achieve better results and be more productive than working individually. Some benefits from collaboration are: Sinergy, Community Awareness, Share resources, Overcome of Obstacles, Avoid Duplication, Access to funding sources (“Benefits of Collaboration” 1).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Reflective Writing (WJ #3)</title>
      <link>http://juancgalan.com/post/writers-journal-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 18:40:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://juancgalan.com/post/writers-journal-3/</guid>
      <description>Writing is an iterative process. Assessing the quality is an important part of any iterative process. This is as true in Software Engineering as it is in Writing. One way to improve the quality of any activity that builds something is to edit it and re-do the parts that have little purpose. This superfluous elements can potentially degrade the flow. However, self-editing and rewriting is a tough process. It requires to detach ourselves from our writing and assess it as a reader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Process (WJ #2)</title>
      <link>http://juancgalan.com/post/writers-journal-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 18:22:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://juancgalan.com/post/writers-journal-2/</guid>
      <description>As a teacher, a question that I often hear from my students is &amp;ldquo;How can I learn X?&amp;rdquo;. One of the best ways to ensure that you will learn is to find out which mechanisms are reqired for learning.
Good teachers often design its courses taking into account different needs that students may have for achieve retention and understanding for the relevant topics. However, is of particular interest for anyone to understand how we learn and what its needed for adquiring knowledge in order to go beyond the course requeriments or to learn skills of particular interest outside of academia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outcomes Reflection (WJ #1)</title>
      <link>http://juancgalan.com/post/writing-journal-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 17:13:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://juancgalan.com/post/writing-journal-1/</guid>
      <description>The Arizona State University offers a course through edx.org called ENG101 English Composition.
I decided to take this course in order to improve my writing skills overall. As researcher, most of my work is published on technical journals that require an specific structure that for us who english is our second language is easy to follow. However, I have found that while is easy to just blindly follow the classic technical writing style, in order to write high quality papers I have to be aware of how I do my writing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>